没阳光了 快回去
We're losing the light Go back
你
You.
这是你的房间吧?
Is it your cell?
你准备越狱 斯科菲尔德先生
You are breaking out of this prison, Mr. Scofield.
你得带上我
And you're taking me with you.
那么
So with this deal
他们到底想从我这得到些什么?
what specifically are they expecting from me?
他们想知道所有的事
They need to know everything.
他们要确认你的消息可靠
They want to confirm that you have viable,
并且能够帮助他们定罪
incriminating information
还要你乖乖地做个证人
and that you can be a cooperative witness.
给我看看照片
Show me the pictures.
没照片看 兄弟
I can't show you the pictures, man.
她死了 迈克
She's dead, Michael.
不是说好了 你最好别来这吗
I thought we agreed it was best for you to not come here.
我得知道这次耽搁会有多大影响
I need to know how this delay is going to affect things.
再给我四天
four more days
要是我能离开这的话
If I'm out of here by then
我仍然能够做到
I can still do it.
我会转告那两兄弟的
I'll let the brothers know.
迈克
Michael.
我看起来怎么样
You like this?
不错
Yeah.
今天是个特殊的日子
It's a special occasion.
我爸爸今天要来看我
My dad's coming today,
我在等他过来
so I'm just gonna wait here till he shows up.
蛮精神的
You look sharp.
谢谢
Thanks.
斯科菲尔德 有访客
Scofield , you have a vistor
-LJ 他还 ? -还活着
-LJ. Is he ? -Alive.
又给了我们4天时间
Giving us four more days.
好
Okay, good.
听着 在交易地点
Listen, back at the exchange point,
我看到了3个尸体袋
I saw three body bags.
你 我 还有LJ的
You, me and LJ,
他们没想放过我们
we weren't getting out of there alive.
我不会再鲁莽行事了
That's the last time I get caught flatfooted.
那就去做你该做的事 林肯
Then do what you got to do, Linc.
我会管好我这里的事 行吗?
As long as I take care of my end, right?
迈克我知道莎拉的事 你很生我的气 但
Michael, I know you're angry with me about Sara, but
你说谎了
You lied.
我不得不说谎
I had to lie.
你儿子是我侄子
Your son is my nephew,
我会为他做一切的
and there's nothing I wouldn't do for him.
但显然
But apparently
你认为我只在意自己的事
apparently you only think I only care about myself.
我知道你关心的不是自己
I know you don't care about yourself,
你关心的是莎拉
but you cared about Sara.
你爱她
You loved her.
我很遗憾
And I'm sorry.
但LJ是我儿子
But LJ's my son.
我 我不能让他有事
I-I couldn't let anything happen to him.
你知道的
You know that.
你利用了我 林肯
You used me, Linc.
你这点和组织倒是挺像的
So I guess you and the Company have something in common.
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
我所有号码都试了一遍
I have tried every number I have.
听着 我会再去总部查查
Listen I will check back in headquarters
看他们怎么说
and see what they say.
别管了
Never mind.
我找到他了
I found him.
蓝色卡特
Carter Blue Label.
你虽然出身平凡
You always had such
却很有品味嘛
high-end taste for a girl from Wheeling.
还不是用我的钱
Since I paid for it
你知道我有多么痛恨四处奔波 格雷琴
You know how much I hate to travel, Gretchen
但是考虑到这里的状况 我不得不破例来一趟
but considering the mess down here, I made an exception.
在我来之前 这里就混乱不堪
It was a mess before I got here.
那现在是时候清理下了
And it's time to clean it up.
今天就做个了结吧
We're ending this today.
来硬的
Bang and burn.
将军 我已经分析过了
General, that was analyzed.
如此做法
What you're asking for
太危险了 更何况
is too dangerous, not to mention
时间上根本来不及
next to impossible with the given time frame.
我认为
I remember
当一大笔钱汇到你海外帐户的时候
a substantial wire transfer to an offshore account
那就意味着我们的字典里没有"不可能"
that took the word"impossible"
难道说
out of the equation or tell me,
是我选错了人?
did I hire the wrong person?
提醒你做事要三思 也是我的工作
I am doing my job when I tell you to seriously reconsider.
那现在 我要按我的意思办了
And now, I have to do my job.
我不是花钱让你做我顾问的
I don't pay you to be my advisor.
你只是执行任务的
You're my operator.
你收到命令 就得完成任务
You have your instructions, now get it done.
不然的话
Beuse if you don't,
你上次在摩苏尔(伊拉克北部城市)
I'll make what happened to you in Mosul
遭受的一切就只是个开头罢了
feel like a massage.
这件事是个错误 格雷琴
This was a big mistake, Gretchen.
你不能老来这里
You can't make a habit of coming to Sona.
我不会了
I won't.
因为我们要来硬的了
Because we're going with the bang and burn .
那等于自寻死路
That's suicide.
我们还有时间呢
We have more time.
我老板想快点完事
My boss wants things to move a bit faster.
那你告诉他这样行不通
Well, tell him you can't pull it off.
这么干我可能会被杀了的
I might get killed if we do this.
不这么干我就会被干掉了
And I might get killed if we don't.
你和我之间
Between you and me,
你认为我会更关心谁?
who do you think I care about more?
看着我 詹姆斯
Look at me, James.
看看我有多认真
See if you can tell how serious I am.
如果你不配合
If you don't play ball,
你就等着把牢坐穿吧
I will leave you in Sona to rot.
我保证
I promise.
5点钟 准备好
Be ready by 5:00.
那时行动
That's when it happens.
一起行动
Everybody goes.
斯科菲尔德如何处置?
What about Scofield?
杀了他
Kill him.
如果有人看到我们俩说话 你知道后果的
You know the consequences if I'm seen talking to you?
军队正在加固所有门窗上的铁栏
The military's reinforcing the bars on all the windows.
能否和长官谈谈
Can you talk to the colonel,
让他暂缓几天?
get him to postpone that for a few days? .
经你昨天这么一闹
After your performance yesterday,
我已经没有发言权了
I have no further sway with the colonel.
那我恐怕你是选了条
Well, then I'm afraid you've brokered your way
根本不可能成功的路来逃生
into an escape plan that no longer exists.
我有办法了
I have an idea.
勒齐
Lechero
等我消息
Wait to hear from me.
怎么了
What?
有些人不想再付保护费给你了
Some of the men don't feel the need to pay their debts anymore.
已经一周了
It's been one week, man,
我们已经少了三个人了
and we lost three men.
现在 如果我们要控制索纳监狱 我们需要人手
Now, if we gonna keep Sona, we're gonna need numbers.
这里我现在谁都不信 尤其是现在
I don't trust nobody here right now especially now.
我只想用自己人
I work with the men I have.
是吗 兄弟?
Really, brother?
你和我
You, me
还有那个废物 就靠我们三个?
and the gimp over there, we gonna run this place?
我想带上克里斯托巴
I want to bring on Cristobal.
他靠得住 老大
He's solid, man.
又是戴伦犹太人
One of them Darrien ghetto boys.
那就带上他吧
Bring him up.
但是我不能保证你什么
But I promise you nothing.
找到任何可以支撑住火箭筒和
Find me anything that can sustain heavy RPGs
轻武器的东西
and small arms.
一支美洲豹 一支步行者
A Cougar, a Stryker.
那不可能
Not gonna happen.
我请示过约克中士 但是
I do have a call in to a Sergeant York, but
计划不会改变
Yeah, that's not going to cut it.
打给苏扎梅尔 让他待命
Call Suezamel, put him on standby,
有需要会找他
tell him we might need him.
有问题吗?
Is there a problem?
我们5点就行动?
We're doing this at 5:00?
我们是可以等到晚上
well we could wait until tonight
除非我们的行动够快
when our guys are moving too fast
眼睛够好使
for our night vision to work properly.
干不干随你
You could even tag along if you want.
快去
Get it done.
(疯狂越狱未遂)
Escape Atrevido Disuelto
你好
Hello.
我找詹姆斯・惠斯勒先生的家人
Yes, I'm trying to locate the family of Mr. James Whistler.
我 我是 他妻子
I-I am his I'm his wife.
你是哪位?
Who's calling?
我叫汤米・戴
My name is Tommy Day.
我是惠斯勒先生的房东
I own the apartment building Mr. Whistler rents from.
他房里有根管子坏了
There's been a busted pipe in his unit that's caused
导致邻居家受到损害
some damage to the apartment next door.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我想你把詹姆斯和其他人弄混了
I think you have confused James with someoneelse.
他没租什么公寓
He's not renting another apartment.
我确定是惠斯勒先生租了我的房子
Oh, I assure you Mr. Whistler is my tenant.
自从他服刑后我就找不到人了
I couldn't find anyone to contact after his conviction,
但是我看到了他的一封话费账单
but when the mail came, I checked his phone bill.
他给这个号码打了很多电话
There were numerous calls to this number.
如果你能过来的话
If you could please come to the apartment,
地址是奥瓦里奥阿贝尔布拉沃40号
the address is 40 AbelBravo in Obarrio,
4单元
Unit 4.
告诉他们英特尔公司说
Tell your men the intel says
巴拿马人无法进入串行存取存储器
the Panamanians have no access to SAM.
喂
Yeah.
有进展了
There's been a development.
又给了我们四天时间
The Company's giving us four more days.
-好的 -问题是
-Okay. -Problem is
我 不知道我们怎么出去
I, uh, I don't know how we're getting out of here.
勒齐或许有办法 我还在等
Lechero might have some ideas, but I'm still waiting
他的消息
to hear from him.
对不起 你现在不方便吗
I'm sorry, is this a bad time for you?
这一天很难熬
It's been an intense 24 hours.
我脑子里很乱
I have things on my mind.
也许和你上一次的探视有关
Yeah, like your last trip to visitation maybe.
怎么 你监视我?
What, you're a spy now?
如果说错了别怪我 不过她看起来
Forgive me if I'm wrong, but she didn't really strike me
不像我喜欢的类型啊
as the girlfriend type.
她是组织派来的
She was Company.
你越狱失败后 她来提醒我
After your failed escape, she came to remind me
我也是在冒险
that I have a stake in this, too,
你似乎忘了这一点
which you seem to have forgotten.
如果你说在筹备另一个越狱计划
So forgive me if I don't jump for joy
别怪我没有兴高采烈
when you say you're working on a plan
因为那个计划可能又会失败
that may very well fail again.
我必须得出去
I've got to get out of here,
无论用什么方法
and it's getting to the point where I don't care how.
明白我的意思了吗
Got what we talked about?
你从没见过我
You never met me.
天哪
Oh, my God.
发生什么事了?
What the hell is going on?
谢尔斯
Shales
奥斯卡・谢尔斯怎么了?
What about Oscar Shales?
他 强奸 杀人 虐待
He raped, killed, tortured.
但我没办法治他罪
I couldn't turn, turn him over
那些混账律师要把他弄出去
to some scumbag lawyer who was just gonna get him off or
不 我只是
or no, no, I just
所以我杀了他
so I killed him.
我感觉 很好
And I felt good.
非常非常好
I felt, I felt really good.
然后你知道吗 我脑海里就一直出现
But then, you know, came the visions
谢尔斯求我放他生路的一幕
of Shales begging for his life,
我摆脱不了
and I couldn't get rid of them,
所以我得靠吃药来保持平静
so I, I got these drugs that kept me on an even keel.
当我到了索纳监狱
And then when I got to Sona,
我拿不到药 所以我不得不
I coul get my pills, so I had to
临时救急
improvise.
要我帮你弄点药吗
Did you want me to get drugs for you?
我确信想让我作证的人
I assume that whoever set this up must think
一定是觉得我还有价值
that I might have some value.
这是你回来找我的原因吧
It's why you came back for me.
我是来帮助一个我敬仰和关心的人
I came here to help a man that I respect and care about.
荣幸之至
And I appreciate that.
但是我现在这个样子没法作证
But I can't testify like this.
求你了
Please
窗户上都加了一英尺厚的强化钢
One inch of reinforced steel on every window.
没人出的去
Nothing would get through those.
我会找到办法的
I'll figure something out.
我知道你会
I know you will.
听着 刚才很抱歉
Listen, man, I'm sorry about before.
就像我说的 事情变得很紧张了
Like I said, things have been intense.
行动成功太重要了
So much depends on this working out.
我侄子的命也取决于这次的行动
My nephew's life depends on this working.
我知道
I know it does.
我还没问过 他多大了?
I never asked how old is he?
16岁
Sixteen.
天哪
Oh, hell.
叮咚 叮咚
Knock knocka.
你来干嘛?
What do you want?
我? 我只是来把一些东西
Me? I just came by to slip something
扔进你的信箱里
into your mail slot.
是老大给的
It's from El Patron himself,
但是只给你们看
but it was made for your eyes only.
收好了
Grabby.
我看这可不像是一个舞会
That don't look like no invitation
邀请函什么的
to the Sona-Hains Dance.
你和勒齐在策划什么事?
What do you got cooking up with Lechero, huh?
不关你的事 蒂博格
It's none of your business, Theodore.
你想对我保密?
You want to keep secrets?
你当我是一支讨厌虫? 随便你
You want to treat me like a pesky insect? Fine.
给我记住 情报 就像面包屑
Just remember, information, like crumbs,
总会撒落在地上让虫子吃掉的
always trickles down to the vermin on the floor.
4点钟?
4:00?
这是勒齐牢房的草图
It's a sketch of Lechero's quarters.
老实说 如果有房客提前支付一年的房租
To be honest, when a tenant pays a year's rent in advance
也不来住的话
and then gets locked up,
我一般都会把这房子再租出去
I normally rent the place out
赚双倍的钱 不过
and double my money, but, uh,
詹姆斯人不错
James was a good man.
我一直希望他的事情可以有转机
I was hoping things would turn out well for him.
我说 夫人
Look, uh, miss
很多人都会有一些自己的秘密
a lot of guys have a little something on the side.
我是说 这个公寓 无论他带谁来过这里
This apartment, I mean, whoever he brought here,
并不意味着他不爱你
doesn't mean he didn't love ya.
你说你这有詹姆斯的保险单?
You said you have James' insurance paper?
稍等 马上
Right on. Right on.
我去给你拿来
I'll, uh, I'll go get them.
哦 我的天
Oh, God.
那儿还有一扇门
There's another door in here.
"4413"
"4413."
4413 对吧
4413, huh?
那斯科菲尔德怎么办
What about Scofield?
干掉他
Kill him.
如果这个草图不是勒齐给我们的
You know, if Lechero didn't send this,
那么这事就是有人派蒂博格算计我的
T-Bag might be setting me up for someone.
我们从这里出去
I say we get out of here.
迈克 你因为我惹上了这么多麻烦 很抱歉
I'm truly sorry you got caught up in my troubles, Michael.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
这儿还有一个密码锁
I take it there's another code.
我是唯一知道的人
I'm the only one that knows it.
对于一个喜欢保密的人
For a man who likes keeping a secret,
选择蒂博格作为送信人
choosing T-Bag as a go-between
可不是一个明智的选择
might not be the smartest move.
是的 不过当他想明白的时候 我们早就跑远了
Yeah, by the time he figures it out, we'll be long gone.
萨米正在回来的路上 走吧
Sammy's on his way back. Let's go.
这是他妈什么?
What the hell's this?
地下通道
Underground tunnel.
原来看守用做
The old administration used it
从A区到B区的通道
to travel between cellblocks A and B.
自从暴动之后 他们把我们都转移到了B区
After the riots, they moved us all to B.
然后当兵的就
And then the soldiers came in,
把这个通道炸了
blew this tunnel up.
看起来有人已经试图打通这些废墟了
Looks like someone already tried to get through the debris.
我可没打算一辈子都待在这里
I never planned to spend my whole life in Sona.
只是没想到这么快就得走了
Just didn't expect it to end so soon.
你是工程师 对吧
You're the engineer, though, right?
我想你能弄条路出去吧?
You can dig our way out of this?
是的 但我需要几个装载机
Yeah, me and a couple of payloaders.
给我听好了
Now, you listen.
你必须得从这里挖出去
You're gonna dig out of this place.
我们不能挖出去 不过我们可以试试向上挖
We're not digging out, but we might be diggin up.
你好 索菲亚
Hello, Sofia.
你好 你是谁
Hello. Who are you?
詹姆斯的一个朋友
Friend of James.
老朋友
Old friend.
他现在不在
Well, he isn't here.
我知道他在哪
I know where he is.
我可知道詹姆斯为什么喜欢你了
I can see why James loves you.
你真漂亮
You are beautiful.
如果你继续到处瞎打探消息
If you keep sticking your nose where
而不乖乖待着的话
it doesn't belong,
我会让他再也见不到你的
I'm gonna make him miss you very, very much.
你知道我的意思了吧
Do you understand what I'm saying to you?
很好
Good.
这个不需要你来操心
You don't need to worry about this.
听清楚了索菲亚 这样你才不会受到伤害
Now listen very carefully to me, Sofia, and you won't get hurt.
我要你回家待着 做做头发
I want you to go home and do your hair
涂好指甲 准备好
and paint your nails and get all ready
等着詹姆斯回家
for when James comes home.
然后你们就幸福地过一辈子
You two will live happily ever after.
你想从他这儿得到什么
What do you want from him?
瞧 你又不听话了
See? You're not listening already.
别插手这事
Don't get in the way,
不然你会很难堪的
or I promise you things will get very bad for you.
你真的很漂亮
You are truly beautiful.
我希望你可以始终这样
I hope you can stay that way.
现在滚吧
Get the hell out of here
好吧 如果我们可以穿过天花板
All right, if we can get through
地基 还有上面的土层
the ceiling, the foundation and the earth on top othat,
我们就可以上到禁入区了
we can make it out into the middle of no-man's-land
然后我们可以在被击中之前到达围栏
and maybe hit the fence before we get shot.
是啊 我们可不想被射死
Yeah. Well, we wouldn't want that.
对的 不过你确实可以挖通 对吧
Yes, but you can dig out, though, right?
根据重力学和索纳地下的沙质情况来看
Based on gravity and the kind of sand that Sona's built on,
我们在挖掘时需要支柱来支撑这个通道
we're gonna need some kind of support brace for the tunnel.
不然的话
Or
不然怎样?
Or what?
不然整个隧道会坍塌 我们就会被活埋
The whole thing collapses and we're buried alive.
大家随便点
Go on and relax, huh?
我去弄点朗姆酒来
I'll get some rum.
这要花多久时间
How long will this take?
大约两天
Maybe two days.
我得上楼去看看 估算我们
I got to get upstairs, estimate exactly where
从隧道出去后到底处于禁入区的什么方位
in no-man's land that tunnel's gonna let out.
你去哪 我正考虑问题呢
Where you going? I'm meditating.
来给克里斯托巴和他的人弄点朗姆酒
Just getng rum for Cristobal and his boys.
朗姆酒? 给他的人
Rum? His boys?
我确实说过愿意见见克里斯托巴
No, I said I'd meet with Cristobal,
但不是一大堆人
not every half-breed in Sona.
不过 他们现在正在上面呢
Well, they up there right now.
那我们走
So, let's go.
-让我给他们弄点朗姆酒吧 -没门
-Let me just get some rum, now. -No, man.
让他们向其他人一样喝啤酒好了
Then drink beer like everyone else.
我说 哥们 给他们点好东西
Look, man, offer them something good.
不要让我难堪
Don't make me look fool.
这酒是我的 萨米
The rum is for me, Sammy.
我说不行
No?
你有意见吗
You have a problem with that?
没意见 先生
No, sir.
很好
Good.
那我们走吧
Let's go.
我们继续干吧
Let's get back to work.
只有勒齐才知道密码
Hey, only Lechero has the code.
我们不需要密码
We don't need a code.
进去
Now, get inside.
在萨米回来之前
before Sammy comes back.
阿历克斯
Alex?
兰探员呢
Where's Agent Lang?
她 不知道
Agent I don't know.
你这是怎么了 发生什么了吗
But what the hell's wrong with you? What's going on?
我有权紧张
I have a right to be nervous.
我的处境很危险 不是吗
My life is on the line, you know?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你以前总是召开现场记者招待会
You have given live press conferences your entire life.
我见过很多次了 你是老手了
I've seen you many times. You're an old pro.
去洗个脸
Now, splash some water on your face.
陪审团让我们现在就去 马上
The panel wants us there right now, immediately.
-什么? -穿好衣服
-What? -Get dressed.
还是你想让我
Or would you rather have me
把你再送回索纳?
drag your ass back to Sona?
洗洗脸 穿上西装 我们现在就走
Water on the face. Get your suit on. We're going.
是 这是苏林斯
Yeah, it's Sullins.
我们马上就出发了
Uh, we're almost ready to move here.
兰到底去哪了
Where the hell is Lang?
不
No.
我们进展如何
Where are we at?
一切就绪
Everything's in place.
不错 我们准备好了
Good. We've done our part.
现在就等惠斯勒了
Now it's time for Whistler to step up and do his.
5点过来 他最好准备好了
Come 5:00, he better be ready.
打通三尺厚的钢筋混凝土
Three feet of concrete and rebar,
和10尺的泥沙
plus ten feet of dirt and sand,
我们就能看见外面了
before we see sky.
你怎么了
Are you all right?
老实说
To be completely honest
不好
no,
一点儿都不
not really.
我不能呆在狭窄的空间里
I have this thing for, uh, confined spaces.
你有幽闭恐怖症?
Are you telling me you're claustrophobic?
从我还是个
Ever since I was a
孩子的时候
boy.
我必须上去
Um, you know, I need to be upstairs.
现在不行
That's not really an option right now.
我真的不能呆在这里
Well, staying here is not really an option for me, either.
振作一下
I suggest you get yourself togetr.
我去透透气
I just need some air.
你到底怎么了
What the hell's the matter with you?
-我得出去透透气 -如果你现在上去
-I need to get out of here; I need air. -Hey, you walk
萨米就在那里
through that door with Sammy on the other side,
你上去就死定了
you'll never need air again.
你不明白的 我得离开这里
You don't understand,I need to get out of here now.
告诉我究竟发生了什么惠斯勒
Why don't you tell me what's really going on here, Whistler?
你干嘛总看表
Why do you keep looking at your watch?
你到底要去哪
What are you really up to?
斯科菲尔德 他们走了 快走
Scofield, the men are gone, let's move.
我想用一下手机
I need your cell phone.
不行 萨米马上就回来了 离开这里
No, Sammy's on his way, get out of here.
-我得打电话给我哥 -不行 手机得放我这
-I have to call my brother. -No, cell phone stays with me. Now,
赶紧离开这儿
get out of here
美国佬 我们得说说清楚
Well, just so that we're clear, Americano,
这房子没通电 没有自来水
she's got no electricity and no running water.
而且屋里没有卫生间 但是林子里可以方便
Septic's out, too, but there's an outhouse in the woods.
-不错 一个月100 -200
It's perfect. A hundred bucks a month. $200.
就100块
A hundred bucks a month.
成交
Deal.
但是不准种毒品
But I don't want growing no drugs on the land.
也不准种大麻
No marijuana.
听见了吗
You got that?
-欢迎回家 朋友 -谢了
-Welcome home, my friend. -Thanks.
哥们儿 如果你现在不想干了
Listen, man, if you want to get out of here,
我会理解的 迈克也会的
I'd get it and Michael would, too.
你已经做了很多了
You've done more than enough.
如果换作我儿子被绑架
If I had a kid in the same situation as your son,
你们兄弟俩会帮我吗
would you and your brother walk out on me?
当然会了
Yeah.
这里就行
Here, this is good.
把它放在这
Put it down there.
拿好
Okay, hold on.
准备好了?
You ready?
是的
Yeah.
我希望这能管用 伙计
I hope this works, papi.
我们走
All right, let's go.
麦格雷迪
McGrady.
帮我个忙
I need your help.
现在不行 我爸爸已经到了 我得出去见他
Not now, bro my father finally got here; I'm gonna go see him.
事实上 我也需要他的帮助
Actually, uh, I need his help, too.
你想让他干什么
What you want from my old man?
我只是想找个信任的人
I just need someone to deliver
能在外面帮我传个消息
a message on the outside, someone I can trust.
不 我爸爸性格很直
Hell, no. My papa's straight as razor blade.
他不想惹事上身
He don't get into kind of trouble like you do.
-不会惹麻烦的 只是打个电话 -不
-It's not trouble, it's just a phone call. -No.
我爱我爸爸
I love my father.
我也爱我哥哥 如果他没有收到消息的话
And I love my brother, and if he doesn't get this message
就会发生可怕的事
something horrible's gonna happen to him.
听着非常不好的事情就会发生
Look something really bad is going on.
求你了
Please.
你好吗 儿子
Hello, son.
爸爸
Papa.
你看起来很帅嘛
You look very handsome.
像你以前在学校照片里的样子
Like your school picture.
谢谢
Gracias.
我帮一个人清扫了房间 换来了这个衬衫
I cleaned a guy's cell for this shirt.
你现在应该在学校的
You should be in school now
-没关系 爸爸 -和你的朋友们
It's okay, Papa. with your friends.
求你了爸爸 别难过
Papa, please, don't get upset.
我在这里也有朋友的
I-I have friends in here.
那个美国人?
The American?
是的 他很好
Yes. He's Nice.
他很守信用 在索纳很少见到这样的人
He keeps his word, it's very rare in Sona.
还有
And, uh
他需要我帮忙
he needs my help.
能见到你真好
Thank God you're here.
我还以为你会早点儿来
Thought you might have come a little earlier,
看看我呢
just to make sure I was okay.
我读了报纸 知道你还好
I read the newspaper I knew you were safe.
我是 至少现在 但你有可能会不安全
I am for now but you might not be.
仔细听我说
Now, listen to me carefully.
答应我今天不要去找林肯・布鲁斯
Promise me you won't go anywhere near Lincoln Burrows today.
-林肯? -真的很危险
-Lincoln? -It's just too dangerous
只要接近他 就会有危险
to be around him, to be with him, to be near him.
回家呆着
Just go home and stay there,
我今天晚上给你打电话
and I will call you tonight.
我只能说这些
That's all I can say.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
-打给我? 从哪打? -你究竟明不明白
-Call me? From where? -Do you understand me?
明白
Yeah.
答应我
Promise me.
大声说出来
Say it out loud.
我保证
I promise.
你在害怕什么?
Why are you so scared?
因为我不能让你受到伤害
Because I can't have you get hurt.
因为我爱你胜过一切
Because I love you more than anything in the world.
是吗?
Do you?
当然
Yeah.
詹姆斯
James,
今天我接到一个电话
I got a call today
他说是你的房东
from a man who said he's your landlord.
另一个公寓的
Talking about another apartment.
我要给他回话吗?
Should I call him back?
肯定是打错了
Must have been a wrong number.
他指名道姓要找你
He asked for you by name.
他一定是糊涂了
The man is clearly confused.
我不知道什么另一个公寓
I don't know anything about another apartment.
索菲亚
Sofia,
我只知道你得离林肯远点
all I know is that you've got to stay away from Lincoln.
拜托了
Please.
好的 詹姆斯
Okay, James.
我会等你的电话
I'll wait for your call.
看
Here.
我给你带了这个
I have this.
我不想看
I don't want to see it.
我会把它跟其他的放在一起
I'll put it with the others.
我回不了家了
I'm not coming home.
接受现实吧
Accept that.
你该走了
You should go.
记得替我朋友打电话
Make that call for my friend.
生日快乐 儿子
Happy birthday, son.
也许我们应该弄些锁
Maybe we should pick up some locks
-把那房子锁起来 -不能让它有所改变
and secure the house. It can't have anything new on it.
那地方得弄成像是废弃的
The place needs to look abandoned.
喂
Yeah?
我给你带条口信
I have a message for you.
不要回家吃晚饭
Don't come home for dinner.
你是谁
Who is this?
我只负责告诉你
I'm supposed to tell you,
不要回家吃晚饭
don't come home for dinner.
什么?
What?
小时候 我和迈克
When me and Mikey were kids,
有一套暗号 用来对付
we had a code when Social Services
那些想把我关进少管所的人
were trying to get me into juvie.
这是他让我小心的暗号
He's telling me to watch my back.
你在这干什么呢
What the hell are you doing here?
你怎么不回我电话 也不还我车?
Why haven't you returned my calls or my car?
你看见他了吗
You have him?
他刚回酒店
Yeah, he just arrived back at his hotel.
但是惠斯勒的女朋友也找到他了
But Whistler's girl tracked him down.
她正在跟
And she's talking
林肯和那个墨西哥人说话
to Lincoln and the Mexican.
她昨天看到了那些东西 一定会让事情复杂化
After what she saw today, she could be complicating things.
你警告她了吗
You have a directive?
我说过了
I warned her.
把他们都干掉
Take them all out.
那惠斯勒会怎样?
What will Whistler say?
我说把他们都干掉
I said take them all out
我不关心你男朋友
I don't care about your boyfriend's apartment
在那里的公寓 不关我的事
on the side, I just don't care.
不 我去了那里
No, I went there.
然后一个女人来了
And a woman showed up;
她威胁我
she threatened me.
她认识詹姆斯
She knows James.
苏珊
Susan.
你认识她?
You know her?
LJ就在她手上
She's the one who has LJ.
她拿走了我发现的一些东西
Well, she took something I found,
一本护照
a passport.
上面有詹姆斯的照片和生日
It had James' picture and birthday
但名字写的是格雷・米勒
but his name said Gary Miller.
林肯我不明白是怎么回事
Lincoln, I don't know what's going on.
我告诉你怎么回事
I'll tell you what's going on
你男朋友是个骗子
your boyfriend's a liar.
我一早就说过了
I told you that from the start.
詹姆斯让我今天离你远点
James told me to stay away from you today,
因为会很危险
that it was dangerous.
我们上
Let's go.
等一下
Pronto.
我要找迈克・斯科菲尔德
I need to speak to Michael Scofield.
我是他哥哥
I'm his brother.
你怎么知道这个号码的
How you get this number?
他几天前给我打过电话
He called a few days back.
我没接
I-I didn't answer.
听着 我现在需要跟他讲话
But, listen, I-I need to speak to him now.
跟上
Let's go.
你绝对猜不到 是迈克・斯科菲尔德的哥哥
You'll never guess Michael Scofield's brother.
谁给我打电话
Who calls me
我打给谁
and who I call,
都是我的事
is my business.
你的朋友呢
Where are your friends?
我不知道
I don't know.
在哪里
Where are your friends?
我不知道 求你别开枪
I don't know, Please don't shoot. Please.
扔掉枪
Drop it.
你为什么纠缠不休?
Why are you coming after this?
一切又重演了是吗 林肯
Different day, same problem, huh, Lincoln?
那天LJ也这样在我手里 你知道后果的
You know how it turned out when LJ was in this position,
今天也是一样
and today is no different
所以乖乖地放下枪
so be a good boy and put down the gun.
快点 林肯
Come on, Linc.
我知道你已经有过次教训了
I know you've learned your lesson.
你说得对 我是有了
You're right, I have.
我郑重声明
For the record,
这是美国政府要求举行的
this is an international hearing,
一次国际听证会
requested by the United States government,
目的是听取阿历克斯・马宏先生的证词
for the purpose of hearing testimony from one Mr. Alexander Mahone.
你不是开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
马宏先生
So, Mr. Mahone,
你第一次接触
when were you first contacted by anyone
这个所谓的"组织"是什么时候
from the group referred to the Company?
他们告诉我
They told me
如果我不把福克斯河越狱的8个人都杀掉
that if I didn't kill every one of the Fox River Eight,
他们就会来对付我
that they would come after me.
那些人都跟斯科菲尔德一起
They had all worked with-with Scofield
执行了越狱计划
on-on-on the escape,
所以"组织"不确定他们到底知道了什么
so the Company wasn't sure what they knew.
马宏先生 请你
Mr. Mahone, I'm going to ask you
不要答非所问
to please keep your answer related to the question.
这些其实都互有关联的
It's-it's all connected.
它是个 是张复杂的大网
It's just it's-it's a web.
我身陷在这个网里
And-and it's a web that I got caught in.
林肯・布鲁斯被卷入其中
And-and Lincoln Burrows got caught in,
迈克・斯科菲尔德也是
and Michael Scofield got caught in.
我如果可以
I, if I may,
我想马宏先生是想说
I think what Mr. Mahone
-我们都像苍蝇一样 -我是说
-We're all just like flies -was trying to say
谢谢你 苏林斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Sullins,
但我们要听的是马宏先生的证词
but we're here to hear from Mr. Mahone.
现在 我们再来一次
Now, we're going to try this again.
你什么时候第一次接触到
When were you first contacted
组织?
by the Company?
我不能说
I cannot say.
你知道
You know
他们什么时候联络你 或者
they could be in contact with you or-or-or
什么时候你被联络 都是未知的
you could be in contact with them, you'd never know.
他们也许现在正在联络我们
It's-it's they could be in contact with us right now.
我知道
I know
这听起来太疯狂了 不是么?
it sounds crazy, right?
简直疯了
It's crazy and
但这很有可能 而事实上
and it would be, except for the simple fact that
的确如此
It's true.
我为之卖命的政府
The government that I had dedicated my life to
操纵和威逼我
Manipulate and extorted me.
并勒索我
Blackmailed me.
所以我才为他们杀人
So that I would kill for them.
我所做的一切都是他们逼的
And I did the things that they made me do
因为我要保护我的家人
so I could protect my family.
所以
And so
我想回家
I would like to go home.
我能回家么?
So can I do that, please?
你去哪了?
Where have you been?
我去找了
I came looking
能支撑地道的废铁
for scrap metal for the support brace for the tunnel.
当真?
Really?
我看来上面挺挤的
Looks like a pretty tight squeeze up there.
你肯定那里有充足的氧气
You sure there's enough fresh air,
还是只有幽闭病人才会来这种地方?
or does the claustrophobia come and go?
为什么总是如此不信任别人呢?
What's it like going through life always distrustful?
你告诉我 詹姆斯
You tell me, James.
不想打断你们的争吵 先生们
Hate to break up the brouhaha, gentlemen,
但勒齐想见你
but Lechero would like to see you.
想和你聊聊你大哥的事
Says it has something to do with your big brother.
让我们单独待会好吗 蒂博格?
Give us a moment, will you, Teodoro?
如果你哥再给我打电话
If your brother should ever call my cell phone again,
告诉他你会因此付出代价的
you tell him you're the one that's gonna pay.
喂
Yeah?
-你收到消息了 -是的 你是对的
-You got the message. -Yeah, you were right.
他们刚想把我们干掉呢
They just tried to take us out.
我知道
I know.
组织的人曾来探视过惠斯勒
Whistler got a visit from the Company.
从那之后他行为就很反常
He's been acting strange ever since.
林肯 我告诉你 肯定出事了
I'm telling you, Linc, something's up.
兄弟 还有比行为反常更严重的
Doing more than acting strange, man.
他告诉索菲亚别接近我
He just told Sofia not to be
因为这很危险
near me 'cause it's dangerous.
组织盯上我们了
The Company's coming after us.
他们不再需要我们了
They don't need us anymore.
准备行动
Here we go.
他们要自己动手帮他越狱了
They're breaking him out on their own.
我们距离目标100码
We're 100 yards from the target.
保持警惕 行动要快
Keep your eyes open. Let's get in and out fast.
来吧
Come on
糟了
Damn
快点
Come on
快点 加把劲
Come on Keep it coming
快啊
Come on Hey
我看到了一架直升机和两名狱徒
I've got a helicopter and two inmates.
我看不清他们的脸 但他们在屋顶
I can't make out their faces, but they're on the roof
快啊
Come on
看不清楚
Can't get a clean shot
我降低高度 带他们走
I'll get lower, take 'em out
是斯科菲尔德和惠斯勒在屋顶上吗
Is that Scofield on the roof with Whistler?
毫无疑问
Is that really a question?
他死定了
He's supposed to be dead.
有人中枪 有人中枪
Man down. Man down.
快走 我要掉下去了
Let go I'm slipping.
惠斯勒掉下去了 行动中止 行动中止
We lost Whistler. Abort. Abort.
任务失败
Mission failure.
马上返回一号基地
Return to Base One immediately.
阿历克斯
Alex
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不得不把你送回索纳监狱
I'm going to have to take you back to Sona.
你 起来
You, get up.
走
Vamos
斯科菲尔德先生
Mr. Scofield,
两天内发生了两起越狱未遂事件
there have been two escape attempts in the past two days.
我相信这不是偶然
Somehow I don't think it's a coincidence
都发生在你来后不久
that you arrived shortly before they happened.
我与此事无关
I had nothing to do with that.
你在索纳惹事太多
You've caused too many problems here in Sona,
或许你不该留在索纳
so maybe you shouldn't be here in Sona.
把他带走
Get him out.
和索纳说再见吧 斯科菲尔德先生
Say good-bye to Sona, Mr. Scofield.